http://www.jdsupra.com/law-news/privacy/

- Unfollow
Refine your interests.
Read Privacy Law updates, news, and legal commentary from leading lawyers and law firms:
Life With GDPR: Episode 50-The Experian Enforcement Notice Case
Cross-Border Data Transfers and the EU-US Data Privacy Tug of War
Does Cellular 5G Equal 5x the Fraud and Misconduct Risk?
Privacy Concerns When Contact Tracing in the Health Care Workplace - Diagnosing Health Care Podcast
Compliance Perspectives: Compliance Challenges in India
This Week in FCPA-Episode 231 – the 50 Days to Inauguration edition
SARS and Liability Issues under GDPR
Compliance and Coronavirus- Tori Reichman on in the increase of cyber-bullying during COVID
Compliance into the Weeds: A Mayor, Covid-19 and Leadership
Everything Compliance-Episode 69, the Biden Administration
Sitting with the C-Suite: How Do Corporations Manage the Convergence of Data during Remote Work?
On-Demand Webinar | Protecting Information in a Work-From-Home World
Compliance and Coronavirus- Mike Lindsey on Cyber Risks in the Era of Covid-19
DHS and Cyber: What Should Companies Expect?
Innovation in Compliance
- Building Trust & Communication Thru Internal Reporting w/ Tori Reichman
Daily Compliance News: November 17, 2020-Jay, We hardly Knew Ye edition
FCPA Compliance Report-Episode 524- Dave Lefort, Reflections on Tommy Heinsohn
Episode 169 -- DOJ Files Antitrust Case Against Google
Daily Compliance News: November 14, 2020-1st Female GM edition
STAKE: The Leadership Podcast - Increase Productivity by Doing THIS!
New Internet of Things Cybersecurity Bill Enacted
Perkins Coie on 12/10/2020
Internet of Things (IoT) devices have the potential to transform our home and work environment by integrating a growing range of “smart” wirelessly connected sensors into our daily lives. Recognizing the growing importance of...more
Top Five Health-Care Privacy, Security Developments to Watch in 2021
WilmerHale on 12/10/2020
Health-care privacy is at a crossroads. For almost 20 years, the health-care industry has addressed the requirements of the HIPAA Privacy and Security Rules, building reasonable and appropriate compliance programs from an...more
Newly Formulated Contract Terms Are the Key to EU-US Data Transfers
Womble Bond Dickinson on 12/10/2020
On December 2, 2020, the European Commission and the European Union (“EU”) foreign affairs service issued a joint statement with goals for the EU’s relationship with the United States. The statement highlighted areas of...more
This Week at the Ninth: Trans Fat and Stolen Emails
Morrison & Foerster LLP - Left Coast Appeals on 12/10/2020
This week, we take a look at one Ninth Circuit decision addressing the difficult Article III issues that arise in certain types of consumer class actions, and another in which the Ninth Circuit examined the application of the...more
The California Privacy Rights Act Has Passed
CompliancePoint on 12/10/2020
In a busy election season, and with many ballot initiatives to take up room, the California Consumer Privacy Rights Act (CPRA) passed with a 56% majority, ushering in a new wave of privacy requirements for companies doing...more
AB-713 CCPA Requirements Take Effect January 1, 2021 for Use of De-identified Health Data Sets
Troutman Pepper on 12/10/2020
On September 28, California Governor Gavin Newsom signed AB-713 into law, which more closely aligned the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) with the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996...more
New Federal Law Alert: The Internet of Things (IoT) Cybersecurity Improvement Act of 2020 – IoT Security for Federal...
Robinson+Cole Data Privacy + Security Insider on 12/10/2020
There is a new federal IoT law, H.R. 1668, the IoT Cybersecurity Improvement Act of 2020, that recently passed the House and Senate and was signed by the President on December 4. ...more
As Voice Recognition Technology Market Surges, Organizations Face Privacy And Cybersecurity Concerns
Jackson Lewis P.C. on 12/10/2020
A new report released by Global Market Insights, Inc. last month estimates that the global market valuation for voice recognition technology will reach approximately $7 billion by 2026, in main part due to the surge of AI and...more
2020 State Consumer Privacy Law Round-Up
Davis Wright Tremaine LLP on 12/10/2020
As the year draws to a close, it seems safe to declare that 2020 was not a good year for the enactment of state consumer privacy legislation. Below, we provide status updates on state privacy task force initiatives and...more
Brexit and Data Protection: What You Need to Know
Alston & Bird on 12/10/2020
With the end of the Brexit transition period around the corner, companies doing business in the EU and UK must prepare for data protection change – and not only international data transfers. Our Privacy & Data Security Team...more
President Signs IoT Cybersecurity Act of 2020
Kelley Drye & Warren LLP on 12/10/2020
On December 4, 2020, President Trump signed bipartisan legislation establishing minimum security requirements for Internet of Things (“IoT”) devices used by the federal government. The legislation, H.R. 1668, passed the House...more
Life With GDPR: Episode 50-The Experian Enforcement Notice Case
Thomas Fox on 12/10/2020
In this episode Jonathan Armstrong and Tom Fox are back to discuss issues relating to data privacy, data protection and GDPR. Today, we consider the Experian enforcement action. Recently, the UK Data Protection Authority, the...more
Canada Introduces the Consumer Privacy Protection Act
Knobbe Martens on 12/9/2020
On November 17, 2020, the Canadian House of Commons introduced the Digital Charter Implementation Act, 2020 (“DCIA”), which includes the Consumer Privacy Protection Act (“CPPA”), a privacy focused arm of the legislation. The...more
Security Implications of Foreign Funding and Access at U.S. Colleges and Universities
Manatt, Phelps & Phillips, LLP on 12/9/2020
While global media outlets have focused attention on election security, major U.S. healthcare facilities have been under direct cyberattacks in recent months. This follows disruptive cyberattacks on municipalities earlier...more
Cyber Attackers Threaten COVID-19 Vaccine Distribution Chain
Faegre Drinker Biddle & Reath LLP on 12/9/2020
As COVID-19 vaccine approvals and eventual distribution kicks into high gear, there has been a corresponding – and not particularly surprising – increase in cyber threat activity targeting both vaccine producers and other...more
Shareholder Seeks Second Look At Company Data Security Practices
Proskauer - Minding Your Business on 12/9/2020
On November 25, 2020, a shareholder of First American Financial Corporation (“First American”) filed suit against the company and its officers and directors over a massive data security breach that exposed hundreds of...more
Pardon My Drone
Womble Bond Dickinson on 12/9/2020
If we think about drones, we probably think about remote-controlled assassination machines manned by the Mossad or “fly-through” tours of the homes of the rich and famous.
What we (or at least I) didn’t think about were...more
President Trump Signs IoT Cybersecurity Measure into Law
Akin Gump Strauss Hauer & Feld LLP on 12/9/2020
On Friday, December 4, 2020, President Donald Trump signed H.R. 1668, the Internet of Things (IoT) Cybersecurity Improvement Act of 2020, into law. The measure, which was approved by the House of Representatives in September...more
Supreme Court Hears Oral Argument In Highly Anticipated Case Addressing The Reach Of The Telephone Consumer Protection Act
Polsinelli on 12/9/2020
Yesterday, the U.S. Supreme Court heard oral argument in Facebook v. Duguid—a significant case potentially limiting the reach of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act (“TCPA”). Facebook will resolve a circuit split over what...more
Financial Daily Dose 12.9.2020 | Top Story: DoorDash Makes Public Trading Debut North of $100/share
Robins Kaplan LLP on 12/9/2020
DoorDash is entering the public markets fray today with hopes of “cash[ing] in on the frenzy in initial public offerings” of late. The food-delivery company is expected to price shares “at the high end of or above its...more
Embraer Data Leaked on Darkweb Website
Robinson+Cole Data Privacy + Security Insider on 12/9/2020
Brazilian airplane manufacturer Embraer’s data has reportedly been uploaded on a dark web website hosted by ransomware group RansomExx (a/k/a Defray 777) after Embraer reportedly refused to pay a ransom following a ransomware...more
Harnessing Big Data – Draft EU Data Governance Regulation aims to increase innovators’ access to data
Dechert LLP on 12/9/2020
A new draft EU Regulation aims to encourage the sharing and re-use of data and foster a data-driven economy that shares the benefits of Big Data whilst respecting individuals’ rights in personal data and commercial rights in...more
Pursuing the ‘Con Queen of Hollywood’
K2 Integrity on 12/9/2020
K2 Integrity associate managing director Nicoletta Kotsianas has been the driving force behind the identification of an international scam artist and a critical ally of law enforcement in its pursuit of the...more
Cruise Industry Compliance Tips: Enhancing the Traveler Experience with Facial Recognition
Blank Rome LLP on 12/9/2020
In the past few years, the commercial use of facial recognition technology has advanced at an explosive rate, expanding into numerous industries and trades. For instance, facial biometrics is increasingly relied on by...more
Coronavirus: The Hill and the Headlines, December 2020 # 6
Hogan Lovells on 12/9/2020
In Washington:
POLITICO reporter Burgess Everett tweeted that Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-KY) says “negotiators should drop both state and local aid and liability shield provisions in order to reach consensus...more
27,173
Results
/
View per page
15
25
50
Page:
1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
of 1,087
Next »
Explore Related Topics
Cybersecurity
Data Privacy
Data Protection
California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)
Data Collection
Popular
Personal Data
Data Security
Consumer Privacy Rights
Coronavirus/COVID-19
General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
EU
Personally Identifiable Information
Data Breach
International Data Transfers
See all ›
Follow Privacy Updates on:
What's Your Interest?
All Subjects
Administrative Agencies
Agriculture
Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR)
Antitrust & Trade Regulation
Art, Entertainment, & Sports
Bankruptcy
Business Organizations
Business Torts
Civil Procedure
Civil Remedies
Civil Rights
See more
Find a Privacy Author »
Trending Now
Ransomware
RegTech
Age Discrimination
Wage Theft Protection
Class Actions
The NLRB
Chief Compliance Officers
Gig Economy
"My best business intelligence, in one easy email…"
Your first step to building a free, personalized, morning email brief covering pertinent authors and topics on JD Supra:
Sign up
Log in
*By using the service, you signify your acceptance of JD Supra's Privacy Policy.
- hide
JD Supra Privacy Policy
Updated: May 25, 2018:
JD Supra is a legal publishing service that connects experts and their content with broader audiences of professionals, journalists and associations.
This Privacy Policy describes how JD Supra, LLC ("JD Supra" or "we," "us," or "our") collects, uses and shares personal data collected from visitors to our website (located at www.jdsupra.com) (our "Website") who view only publicly-available content as well as subscribers to our services (such as our email digests or author tools)(our "Services").
By using our Website and registering for one of our Services, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy.
Please note that if you subscribe to one of our Services, you can make choices about how we collect, use and share your information through our Privacy Center under the "My Account" dashboard (available if you are logged into your JD Supra account).
Collection of Information
Registration Information.
When you register with JD Supra for our Website and Services, either as an author or as a subscriber, you will be asked to provide identifying information to create your JD Supra account ("Registration Data"), such as your:
Email
First Name
Last Name
Company Name
Company Industry
Title
Country
Other Information: We also collect other information you may voluntarily provide. This may include content you provide for publication. We may also receive your communications with others through our Website and Services (such as contacting an author through our Website) or communications directly with us (such as through email, feedback or other forms or social media). If you are a subscribed user, we will also collect your user preferences, such as the types of articles you would like to read.
Information from third parties (such as, from your employer or LinkedIn): We may also receive information about you from third party sources. For example, your employer may provide your information to us, such as in connection with an article submitted by your employer for publication. If you choose to use LinkedIn to subscribe to our Website and Services, we also collect information related to your LinkedIn account and profile.
Your interactions with our Website and Services: As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the Website and our Services, to improve the content and performance of our Website and Services, and to track users' movements around the site. We may also link this automatically-collected data to personal information, for example, to inform authors about who has read their articles. Some of this data is collected through information sent by your web browser.
We also use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect this information.
To learn more about cookies and other tracking technologies that JD Supra may use on our Website and Services please see our "Cookies Guide" page.
How do we use this information?
We use the information and data we collect principally in order to provide our Website and Services.
More specifically, we may use your personal information to:
Operate our Website and Services and publish content;
Distribute content to you in accordance with your preferences as well as to provide other notifications to you (for example, updates about our policies and terms);
Measure readership and usage of the Website and Services;
Communicate with you regarding your questions and requests;
Authenticate users and to provide for the safety and security of our Website and Services;
Conduct research and similar activities to improve our Website and Services; and
Comply with our legal and regulatory responsibilities and to enforce our rights.
How is your information shared?
Content and other public information (such as an author profile) is shared on our Website and Services, including via email digests and social media feeds, and is accessible to the general public.
If you choose to use our Website and Services to communicate directly with a company or individual, such communication may be shared accordingly.
Readership information is provided to publishing law firms and authors of content to give them insight into their readership and to help them to improve their content.
Our Website may offer you the opportunity to share information through our Website, such as through Facebook's "Like" or Twitter's "Tweet" button.
We offer this functionality to help generate interest in our Website and content and to permit you to recommend content to your contacts.
You should be aware that sharing through such functionality may result in information being collected by the applicable social media network and possibly being made publicly available (for example, through a search engine).
Any such information collection would be subject to such third party social media network's privacy policy.
Your information may also be shared to parties who support our business, such as professional advisors as well as web-hosting providers, analytics providers and other information technology providers.
Any court, governmental authority, law enforcement agency or other third party where we believe disclosure is necessary to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation, or otherwise to protect our rights, the rights of any third party or individuals' personal safety, or to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or safety issues.
To our affiliated entities and in connection with the sale, assignment or other transfer of our company or our business.
How We Protect Your Information
JD Supra takes reasonable and appropriate precautions to insure that user information is protected from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. We restrict access to user information to those individuals who reasonably need access to perform their job functions, such as our third party email service, customer service personnel and technical staff. You should keep in mind that no Internet transmission is ever 100% secure or error-free. Where you use log-in credentials (usernames, passwords) on our Website, please remember that it is your responsibility to safeguard them. If you believe that your log-in credentials have been compromised, please contact us at privacy@jdsupra.com.
Children's Information
Our Website and Services are not directed at children under the age of 16 and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 16 through our Website and/or Services. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 16 has provided personal information to us, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases.
Links to Other Websites
Our Website and Services may contain links to other websites. The operators of such other websites may collect information about you, including through cookies or other technologies. If you are using our Website or Services and click a link to another site, you will leave our Website and this Policy will not apply to your use of and activity on those other sites. We encourage you to read the legal notices posted on those sites, including their privacy policies. We are not responsible for the data collection and use practices of such other sites. This Policy applies solely to the information collected in connection with your use of our Website and Services and does not apply to any practices conducted offline or in connection with any other websites.
Information for EU and Swiss Residents
JD Supra's principal place of business is in the United States.
By subscribing to our website, you expressly consent to your information being processed in the United States.
Our Legal Basis for Processing: Generally, we rely on our legitimate interests in order to process your personal information. For example, we rely on this legal ground if we use your personal information to manage your Registration Data and administer our relationship with you; to deliver our Website and Services; understand and improve our Website and Services; report reader analytics to our authors; to personalize your experience on our Website and Services; and where necessary to protect or defend our or another's rights or property, or to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, safety or privacy issues.
Please see Article 6(1)(f) of the E.U. General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") In addition, there may be other situations where other grounds for processing may exist, such as where processing is a result of legal requirements (GDPR Article 6(1)(c)) or for reasons of public interest (GDPR Article 6(1)(e)). Please see the "Your Rights" section of this Privacy Policy immediately below for more information about how you may request that we limit or refrain from processing your personal information.
Your Rights
Right of Access/Portability:
You can ask to review details about the information we hold about you and how that information has been used and disclosed. Note that we may request to verify your identification before fulfilling your request. You can also request that your personal information is provided to you in a commonly used electronic format so that you can share it with other organizations.
Right to Correct Information: You may ask that we make corrections to any information we hold, if you believe such correction to be necessary.
Right to Restrict Our Processing or Erasure of Information: You also have the right in certain circumstances to ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or to erase your personal information.
Where you have consented to our use of your personal information, you can withdraw your consent at any time.
You can make a request to exercise any of these rights by emailing us at privacy@jdsupra.com or by writing to us at:
Privacy Officer
JD Supra, LLC
10 Liberty Ship Way, Suite 300
Sausalito, California 94965
You can also manage your profile and subscriptions through our Privacy Center under the "My Account" dashboard.
We will make all practical efforts to respect your wishes. There may be times, however, where we are not able to fulfill your request, for example, if applicable law prohibits our compliance. Please note that JD Supra does not use "automatic decision making" or "profiling" as those terms are defined in the GDPR.
Timeframe for retaining your personal information: We will retain your personal information in a form that identifies you only for as long as it serves the purpose(s) for which it was initially collected as stated in this Privacy Policy, or subsequently authorized. We may continue processing your personal information for longer periods, but only for the time and to the extent such processing reasonably serves the purposes of archiving in the public interest, journalism, literature and art, scientific or historical research and statistical analysis, and subject to the protection of this Privacy Policy. For example, if you are an author, your personal information may continue to be published in connection with your article indefinitely. When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.
Onward Transfer to Third Parties:
As noted in the "How We Share Your Data" Section above, JD Supra may share your information with third parties. When JD Supra discloses your personal information to third parties, we have ensured that such third parties have either certified under the EU-U.S. or Swiss Privacy Shield Framework and will process all personal data received from EU member states/Switzerland in reliance on the applicable Privacy Shield Framework or that they have been subjected to strict contractual provisions in their contract with us to guarantee an adequate level of data protection for your data.
California Privacy Rights
Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, our customers who are California residents have the right to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.
You can make a request for this information by emailing us at privacy@jdsupra.com or by writing to us at:
Privacy Officer
JD Supra, LLC
10 Liberty Ship Way, Suite 300
Sausalito, California 94965
Some browsers have incorporated a Do Not Track (DNT) feature. These features, when turned on, send a signal that you prefer that the website you are visiting not collect and use data regarding your online searching and browsing activities. As there is not yet a common understanding on how to interpret the DNT signal, we currently do not respond to DNT signals on our site.
Access/Correct/Update/Delete Personal Information
For non-EU/Swiss residents, if you would like to know what personal information we have about you, you can send an e-mail to privacy@jdsupra.com. We will be in contact with you (by mail or otherwise) to verify your identity and provide you the information you request. We will respond within 30 days to your request for access to your personal information. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. If you would like to correct or update your personal information, you can manage your profile and subscriptions through our Privacy Center under the "My Account" dashboard.
If you would like to delete your account or remove your information from our Website and Services, send an e-mail to privacy@jdsupra.com.
Changes in Our Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Please refer to the date at the top of this page to determine when this Policy was last revised. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will become effective upon posting of the revised policy on the Website. By continuing to use our Website and Services following such changes, you will be deemed to have agreed to such changes.
Contacting JD Supra
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, your dealings with our Website or Services, or if you would like to change any of the information you have provided to us, please contact us at: privacy@jdsupra.com.
JD Supra Cookie Guide
As with many websites, JD Supra's website (located at www.jdsupra.com) (our "Website") and
our services (such as our email article digests)(our "Services") use a standard technology called a "cookie" and other similar technologies (such as, pixels and web beacons), which are small data files that are transferred to your computer when you use our Website and Services. These technologies automatically identify your browser whenever you interact with our Website and Services.
How We Use Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies
We use cookies and other tracking technologies to:
Improve the user experience on our Website and Services;
Store the authorization token that users receive when they login to the private areas of our Website. This token is specific to a user's login session and requires a valid username and password to obtain. It is required to access the user's profile information, subscriptions, and analytics;
Track anonymous site usage; and
Permit connectivity with social media networks to permit content sharing.
There are different types of cookies and other technologies used our Website, notably:
"Session cookies" - These cookies only last as long as your online session, and disappear from your computer or device when you close your browser (like Internet Explorer, Google Chrome or Safari).
"Persistent cookies"
- These cookies stay on your computer or device after your browser has been closed and last for a time specified in the cookie. We use persistent cookies when we need to know who you are for more than one browsing session. For example, we use them to remember your preferences for the next time you visit.
"Web Beacons/Pixels" - Some of our web pages and emails may also contain small electronic images known as web beacons, clear GIFs or single-pixel GIFs. These images are placed on a web page or email and typically work in conjunction with cookies to collect data.
We use these images to identify our users and user behavior, such as counting the number of users who have visited a web page or acted upon one of our email digests.
JD Supra Cookies. We place our own cookies on your computer to track certain information about you while you are using our Website and Services. For example, we place a session cookie on your computer each time you visit our Website. We use these cookies to allow you to log-in to your subscriber account. In addition, through these cookies we are able to collect information about how you use the Website, including what browser you may be using, your IP address, and the URL address you came from upon visiting our Website and the URL you next visit (even if those URLs are not on our Website). We also utilize email web beacons to monitor whether our emails are being delivered and read. We also use these tools to help deliver reader analytics to our authors to give them insight into their readership and help them to improve their content, so that it is most useful for our users.
Analytics/Performance Cookies.
JD Supra also uses the following analytic tools to help us analyze the performance of our Website and Services as well as how visitors use our Website and Services:
HubSpot -
For more information about HubSpot cookies, please visit legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy.
New Relic - For more information on New Relic cookies, please visit www.newrelic.com/privacy.
Google Analytics - For more information on Google Analytics cookies, visit www.google.com/policies. To opt-out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout. This will allow you to download and install a Google Analytics cookie-free web browser.
Facebook, Twitter and other Social Network Cookies.
Our content pages allow you to share content appearing on our Website and Services to your social media accounts through the "Like," "Tweet," or similar buttons displayed on such pages. To accomplish this Service, we embed code that such third party social networks provide and that we do not control. These buttons know that you are logged in to your social network account and therefore such social networks could also know that you are viewing the JD Supra Website.
Controlling and Deleting Cookies
If you would like to change how a browser uses cookies, including blocking or deleting cookies from the JD Supra Website and Services you can do so by changing the
settings in your web browser. To control cookies, most browsers allow you to either accept or reject all cookies, only accept certain types of cookies, or prompt you every time a site wishes to save a cookie. It's also easy to delete cookies that are already saved on your device by a browser.
The processes for controlling and deleting cookies vary depending on which browser you use. To find out how to do so with a particular browser, you can use your browser's "Help" function or alternatively, you can visit http://www.aboutcookies.org which explains, step-by-step, how to control and delete cookies in most browsers.
Updates to This Policy
We may update this cookie policy and our Privacy Policy from time-to-time, particularly as technology changes. You can always check this page for the latest version. We may also notify you of changes to our privacy policy by email.
Contacting JD Supra
If you have any questions about how we use cookies and other tracking technologies, please contact us at: privacy@jdsupra.com.
- hide
This website uses cookies to improve user experience, track anonymous site usage, store authorization tokens and permit sharing on social media networks.
By continuing to browse this website you accept the use of cookies. Click here to read more about how we use cookies.
Continue
